ecological social and economic
regeneration is really about working
with people in place to help them
nurture and unleash the latent potential
they have to increase the health
wholeness and resilience of that place
it is about increasing bio productivity
of the place by nurturing the amount of
fertile soils by increasing the amount
of standing forests by creating vibrant
productive analog forests and
Agricultural regenerative agriculture
based ecosystems did enable us to shift
from a material culture that is based on
fossil materials and fossil energy to a
material culture that is based on
biomaterials and renewable energy but it
is also about a deeply internal process
that enables us through personal
development to become more effective as
collaborators and shift from a world
that is by and large marked by a story
that is about competitive scarcity that
is about separation and competition to a
story that is about collaborative
abundance and the makes us understand
that we are fundamentally interconnected
that nurtures interbeing
as the predominant state of a
regenerative culture understanding that
by working towards the health and
wholeness the abundance of the system as
a whole I'm working on systemic health
and this since I'm part of this system
this systemic health can only benefit me
so it's not about elbows it's not about
competitions about collaboration and
collaborative abundance in healing
relationships that increase and optimize
the system at the local and regional
scale and doing so in global solidarity
knowledge exchange and collaboration so
it is a global local AG local world in
which we are fully aware of our global
responsibilities but we all do our bit
at the local and regional scale and in
doing so in engaging with regenerative
development we can not only reverse
global warming by drawing down carbon
into soils standing forests and
biomaterials and at the same time
increase opportunities for regional
economies to help themselves to create
more meaningful and locally regenerative
jobs and therefore give meaning to
people and increase collaboration
between people which increases so social
cohesion and all of this is a
win-win-win solution that enables us to
implement all of the 17 SDGs the
sustainable development goals and
implement agenda 2030 but do so not in
grand schemes that are about scaling up
solutions but in local solutions that
are about spreading what works region by
region community by community but always
carefully adapting it to the bio
cultural uniqueness of that place and
this can only be ensured if the
solutions are actually coming out of the
people who live in that place this is
about increasing the capacity for local
decision making and creating the basis
of a future system of governance that is
based on subsidiarity where people
really make the decisions for their
place in their place in all higher
levels of governance at national or an
international level are about
coordinating the collaboration of people
amongst themselves so we can create a
healthier planet community by community
region by region and in doing so the
audacious promise of regenerative
development is to fundamentally redesign
the human presence on earth in ways that
we shift from a predominantly
destructive and exploitative impact to
being a wise
and humble keystone species that
increases the bio productivity of the
the local and global ecosystems and in
doing so we create a regenerative impact
of humanity on the global system
creating conditions conducive to life
creating a healthier more vibrant more
abundant world both for the community of
life and the community the human
community and this also means creating a
future that is more equitable more just
and share helps us to share
collaborative abundance on the local
regional and global scale this is a
massive undertaking and I really hope
that you're just as excited as I am that
this is what our job is calling us to do
this is what we are here for we are on
this planet at this time to do this
fundamental transition this
transformative innovation towards a
regenerative human culture at the local
regional and global scale
thank you